<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><search><entry><title>AI History Timeline: From Turing to Transformers</title><url>/posts/ai-history-timeline/</url><categories><category>articles</category></categories><tags><tag>AI</tag><tag>deep-learning</tag></tags><content type="html"><![CDATA[  I read a bunch of old papers and remembered fragments of the story, Turing’s imitation game, McCarthy’s Dartmouth proposal, ELIZA’s keyword tricks — and wanted to collect a readable timeline so my future self can quickly recall how AI evolved. Below I put the history in plain words, added technical notes where it helps, and suggested why each era mattered to what we see today.
Timeline: The Major Breakthroughs 1950: Turing&#39;s Question - &amp;quot;Can Machines Think?&amp;quot; The beginning of AI started in the early 1950s when a guy called Alan Turing published &amp;quot;Computing Machinery and Intelligence.&amp;quot; In this paper, he proposed an imitation game which is now called the Turing Test.
The test worked like this: imagine three separate rooms where people can&#39;t see each other. In one room is an interrogator (the judge), in another room is a human, and in the third room is a machine. The interrogator asks questions to both the human and machine through text only, and from their responses, the …  ]]></content></entry><entry><title>Support CWS Foundation</title><url>/donate/</url><categories/><tags/><content type="html">  Foundation Mission The CWS Foundation is dedicated to advancing cryptocurrency education through comprehensive research, tutorials, and market analysis. Our mission centers on making complex blockchain concepts accessible to everyone.
How Your Contribution Helps Every contribution received through this platform directly supports:
Advanced Research: In-depth market analysis and blockchain technology studies Educational Content: Comprehensive tutorials and step-by-step guides Community Resources: Tools and resources typically found in premium offerings Open Knowledge: Making professional-grade insights freely available Transparency Commitment All funds collected are exclusively allocated to content development and educational initiatives. These contributions enable us to dedicate more time to research and create higher-quality educational materials that would otherwise be premium content.
Supported Networks We currently accept donations on:
Ethereum Network (ETH) Address: 0x1234567890abcdef1234567890abcdef12345678 Supported Tokens: ETH, USDT Solana Network (SOL) Address: 9WzDXwBbmkg8ZTbNMqUxvQRAyrZzDsGYdLVL9zYtAWWM Supported Tokens: SOL, USDC How to Donate Copy Address: Or copy the wallet address directly Send Crypto: Transfer any supported cryptocurrency Confirmation: Transactions are processed automatically on-chain Your support enables us to continue providing valuable cryptocurrency education and analysis to the community. Thank you for contributing to knowledge sharing in the blockchain space.
  </content></entry><entry><title>About</title><url>/about/</url><categories/><tags/><content type="html"><![CDATA[  Crypto Storyteller (Creator / Media Manager / Educator) Hey I'm Shashi. I'm a content creator and media manager focused on crypto. I've been documenting my learning notes on this blog since 2025.
I'm not an expert in academic research or long-form journalism, but I transform what I learn into concise notes, practical tutorials, and small projects. I use AI heavily to help draft and prototype content, and I rely on tools and experiments to validate ideas. For my core work, I contribute to Netrum Labs, which is an integrated Web3 infrastructure company building a merchant-grade platform that converges payments, multi-chain connectivity, decentralized infrastructure, and an infrastructure AI layer. And I've also been working on an open-source project called Crypto Library on GitHub, which is an A → Z curated library of high-quality resources about blockchain, cryptocurrencies, cryptography, crypto security, tooling, research papers, and hands-on labs.
GitHub hosts the code, and YouTube explains the &quot;why&quot; and &quot;how&quot; this blog explains what I learn.
How I use this blog This site is primarily a learning notebook - short guides, notes, and worked examples that I create while learning and building. Expect practical posts, code snippets, and step-by-step walkthroughs rather than polished research papers.
If something here helped you, consider starring the related GitHub repo or sharing the post, it really helps. If you want to collaborate or ask a question, the fastest place to reach me is via GitHub issues or X (links above).
  ]]></content></entry></search>